Stephen Martin

Area Sales Manager

Address Newry, Crossmaglen, BT359BY

Phone 087-9600438

E-mail stephen.martin@live.ie

Driven Area Sales Manager with over 10 years of experience in a sales and account management capacity with a strong competitive sales drive, adaptability and perseverance.

Well-honed listening skills and problem-solving attitude to uncover needs and overcome objections to close sales and achieve goals within multiple assigned territories.

A strong brand ambassador encouraging referral network growth through excellent ongoing relationship management.

Sales ability is only matched by work ethic

Skills

Territory Management	Excellent
Lead qualification	Excellent
Relationship building	Excellent
Closing strategies	Excellent
Sales presentations	Excellent
Account management	Excellent
B to B sales	Excellent
Direct sales	Excellent
New Business Development	Excellent

Work History

2022-01 - Current

Area Sales Manager

Elavon Financial Services, Donegal, Sligo, Leitrim, Cavan, Monaghan & Louth

• Established strong relationships with major accounts and key decision-makers to increase sales in designated territory.

- Strong sales across both Revenue and Strategic product measurements.
- Remaining in an advisory capacity for sales teams in ePos sales.
- Coordinated and conducted well-organized product presentations and demonstrations to potential customers at seminars and trade shows.
- Led targeted training programs to educate staff on product benefits and service capabilities.
- Built lasting relationships with clients through outstanding customer service interactions.
- Worked diligently to resolve unique and recurring complaints, promoting loyalty and enhancing operations.
- Forecasted sales and established processes to achieve sales objectives and related metrics.

2020-01 - 2022-01 National EPOS Sales Manager

Elavon Financial Services, Dublin

- Collaborated with Sales teams in Ireland and UK to assist with the sales presentation of Elavons ePos offering.
- Coached teams and individual sales staff on selling techniques and methods specific to ePos sales, both in the field and in training classes.
- I achieved and implemented lead generation partners in both the UK and Ireland for generating ePos sales leads.
- I worked very effectively with internal depts in both Elavon and third party providers to enhance our offering through improved communication.
- Sales performance across both countries has improved dramatically throughout my tenure in the role.

2016-12 - 2019-12 **Area Sales Manager**

Elavon Financial Services, Louth, Meath, Kildare, Westmeath & Longford

- Established myself as a strong sales performer in all metrics within my role.
- Demonstrated an exemplary adaptation of CRM reporting and efficiency.
- Collaborated with other Area Sales Managers for cross border sales, enhancing my own reputation within Elavon Ireland as a reliable and genuine brand bearer.
- Notable sales achievement across multiple sectors including Hospitality and Retail with a particular success in ePos sales.
- Became designated contact for two particular trade partners due to the establishment of a strong personal brand among my customers.
- Executed proven strategies to hit sales quota and help company achieve goals.
- Coordinated and conducted well-organized product presentations and demonstrations to potential customers at seminars and trade shows.
- Built lasting relationships with clients through outstanding customer service interactions.

2015-08 - 2016-11 Territory Sales Manager

Paypoint UK, Belfast

 Exceeded targets of all Paypoint product portfolio including, Merchant Service facilities, Sim Cards and ATM sales.

- Successful adoption of CRM reporting facility
- Carefully analyzed data to determine most effective sales strategies eg
 Population data relative to ATM usage potential
- Winner of UK national sales competitions such as 2011 National SIM Card
 Drive and 2014 Simple Payments Sales Incentive
- This role invaluable to me as a broad education across many sales product ranges from Financial Services to FMCG

2007-07 - 2011-08

Business Development Executive

Paypoint Ireland, Dublin

To extend and maintain the network of Paypoint Retail Sites and Credit Unions in twelve counties in the Republic of Ireland. This included sales of home Bill payment Units and Merchant Service terminals.

This role provided my initial education in CRM Proficiency, relationship management, administration skills aswell as initial sales skills.

Education

2008-08 - 2009-05

Nationa; Certificate in Business Studies: Business Studies

Dundalk Institute of Technology - Dundalk, Co Louth, Ireland

Affiliations

Athletics Northern Ireland

Running

A keen runner and member of the Slieve Gullion Running Club. I have some accolades as runner in a selection of different distances across the country.